<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Carlota Castro</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Carlota Castro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of several movies</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog9/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of movies- IMDB dataset Our team has been tasked with an analysis of several factors related to movies. We want to explore, among others, factors on which the financial success of a movie could depend. We will start with a general exploration of the dataset: how many movies belong to each gender category, what is the financial performance of each gender category, and who are the directors. Furthermore, we will delve into ratings distribution and analyse the impact of factors such as Facebook likes and budget on the financial performance of the movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you ever wondered...?</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog8/</guid>
      <description>Where Do People Drink The Most Beer, Wine And Spirits? Our team has been tasked with the analysis of alcoholic beverages consumption per country. Our clients want to know how is the beer, wine and spirits consumption per country. Back in 2014, fivethiryeight.com published an article on alcohol consumption in different countries. We used the dataset from fivethirtyeight.com to perform our exploration.
#The first thing we need to do is loading the relevant datasets!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How has Trump approval rate varied in time?</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog7/</guid>
      <description>Trump’s Approval Margins Our team has been tasked with the analysis of the net approval rate (i.e. approve- disapprove percentages) for the US president Donald Trump throughout his time in office. Does he have a positive or negative approval rate? Have there been any significants increases or decreases in his net approval rate during his time in the White House? To answer these questions, we will look at data on all polls that track the president’s approval obtained from fivethirtyeight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaries</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog6/</guid>
      <description>Is there salary discrimation based on gender? At the last board meeting of Omega Group Plc., the headquarters of a large multinational company, the issue was raised that women were being discriminated in the company, in the sense that the salaries were not the same for male and female executives. A quick analysis of a sample of 50 employees (of which 24 men and 26 women) revealed that the average salary for men was about 8,700 higher than for women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
